Carl Hildebrandt

Ph.D. Candidate, University of Virginia

85 Engineer's Way carl@carl-h.com Charlottesville, VA https://carl-h.com USA, 22903

I specialize in autonomous systems and software testing, focusing on creating and executing test suites that bridge software, hardware, and physical world interactions. Outside academia, I'm an athlete and adventurer, with achievements like summiting Kilimanjaro and competing in the world's largest ultramarathon.

Education

2018 - 2024 University of Virginia, USA
 Ph.D. Computer Science
 Advisor: Dr. Sebastian Elbaum
 Lab: LESS (less-lab-uva.github.io)

 2013 - 2016 University of Pretoria, South Africa
 B.Eng. in Computer Engineering

Distinguished Artifact Award

Experience

2018 –	Research Assistant, LESS Lab, University of Virginia (less-lab-uva.github.io)
2022 - 2022	Graduate Research Intern, Raytheon BBN (www.rtx.com)
2019 - 2022	Head of Technology, Vuetech Health Innovations LLC(www.vuetechhealth.com)
2017 - 2018	Research Assistant, Nimbus Lab, University of Nebraska (www.nimbus.unl.edu)
2016 - 2017	Software Engineer, Cheesecake Trails

Honors & Awards

External

2020

	Feasible and Stressful Trajectory Generation for Mobile Robots (ISSTA)
2018	Best Paper Award on Safety, Security, and Rescue Robotics
	Fire-Aware Planning of Aerial Trajectories and Ignitions (IROS)
Internal	
2023	All-University Graduate Teaching Award
	The University of Virginia - Office of Graduate and Postdoctoral affairs
2022	Graduate Teaching Award
	The University of Virginia - Annual Computer Science Department End-of-Year Awards
2021	Best Poster Design
	The University of Virginia - Computer Science Research Symposium
2020	Best Presentation
	The University of Virginia - Computer Science Virtual Research Symposium

Publications

- NA **Carl Hildebrandt**, Trey Woodlief, and Sebastian Elbaum, "ODD-diLLMma: Making ODD Compliance Checking Tractable with LLM-Driven Sensor Data Analysis," NA (**Under Submission**)
- NA **Carl Hildebrandt**, and Sebastian Elbaum, "Are Autonomous Systems Safe: A Continuous Differential Testing Framework using Large Language Models and Unlimited Real Data," NA (**Under Development**)
- NA Mira Khan, **Carl Hildebrandt**, and Sebastian Elbaum, "From Simulation to Reality: Streamlining Training AI-Based Drone Navigation Software using Mixed-Reality Environments," NA (**Under Development**)
- NA **Carl Hildebrandt**, Brendan Teich, Dylan Callahan, and Borislava I. Simidchieva, "A Framework for Benchmarking Collaborative-Autonomy Behaviors in Robots," NA (**Under Development**)
- Carl Hildebrandt, Meriel von Stein, and Sebastian Elbaum, "PhysCov: Physical Test Coverage for Autonomous Vehicles," in *Proceedings of the 32nd ACM SIGSOFT International Symposium on Software Testing and Analysis (ISSTA)*, ACM, 2023
- Carl Hildebrandt, Wen Ying, Seongkook Heo, and Sebastian Elbaum, "Mimicking Real Forces on a UAV Through a Haptic Suit," in 2023 IEEE International Conference on Robotics and Automation (ICRA), IEEE, 2023
- Carl Hildebrandt, Meriel von Stein, Trey Woodlief, and Sebastian Elbaum, "Preparing Software Engineers to Develop Robot Systems," in 2022 IEEE/ACM 44th International Conference on Software Engineering: Software Engineering Education and Training (ICSE-SEET), IEEE, 2022
- Carl Hildebrandt, and Sebastian Elbaum, "World-in-the-Loop Simulation for Autonomous Systems Validation," in 2021 IEEE International Conference on Robotics and Automation (ICRA), IEEE, 2021, pp. 10912–10919
- Carl Hildebrandt, Sebastian Elbaum, Nicola Bezzo, and Matthew B Dwyer, "Feasible and stressful trajectory generation for mobile robots," in *Proceedings of the 29th ACM SIGSOFT International Symposium on Software Testing and Analysis (ISSTA)*, 2020, pp. 349–362 (Distinguished Artifact Award)
- Carl Hildebrandt, Sebastian Elbaum, and Nicola Bezzo, "Blending kinematic and software models for tighter reachability analysis," in 2020 IEEE/ACM 42nd International Conference on Software Engineering: New Ideas and Emerging Results (ICSE-NIER), IEEE, 2020, pp. 33–36
- Evan Beachly, Carrick Detweiler, Sebastian Elbaum, Brittany Duncan, **Carl Hildebrandt**, Dirac Twidwell, and Craig Allen, "Fire-aware planning of aerial trajectories and ignitions," in *2018 IEEE/RSJ International Conference on Intelligent Robots and Systems (IROS)*, IEEE, 2018, pp. 685–692 (**Best Paper Award**)

Patents

Carl Hildebrandt, Jefferson Griscavage, Victor Aquino, Melony Bennis, and Tien Comlekoglu, Vuetech Health Innovations LLC, "Systems and Methods for Safety, Security and Well-Being of Individuals", Patent No. 11282367

Talks

2023	Carl Hildebrandt "PhysCov: Physical Test Coverage for Autonomous Vehicles", International Sym-
	posium on Software Testing and Analysis, July 19th
2022	Carl Hildebrandt "Preparing Software En- gineers to Develop Robot Systems", International Confer-
	ence on Software Engineering: Software Engineering Education and Training, May 25th
2021	Carl Hildebrandt "World-in-the-Loop Simulation for Autonomous Systems Validation", International
	Conference on Robotics and Automation, May 30th
2020	Carl Hildebrandt "Feasible and Stressful Trajectory Generation for Mobile Robots", International
	Conference on Software Engineering, July 7th
2020	Carl Hildebrandt "Blending Kinematic and Software Models for Tighter Reachability Analysis", In-

Community Service

2022	Artifact Reviewer, IEEE/ACM International Conference on Automated Software Engineering (ASE).
2022	Graduate Student Council, The University of Virginia, Computer Science Department (CSGSG).
2022	Paper Reviewer, IEEE International Conference on Robotics and Automation Society (ICRA)
2021	Student Volunteer, IEEE/ACM International Conference on Software Engineering (ICSE)

ternational Symposium on Software Testing and Analysis, July 21st

Teaching

2022	Supporting instructor, Robotics for Software Engineers, The University of Virginia
2021	Lab Designer and Guest Lecturer, Robotics for Software Engineers, The University of Virginia
2020	Lab Designer and Teaching Assistant, Robotics for Software Engineers, The University of Virginia
2016	Head Teaching Assistant, Data Structures and Algorithms in Java, The University of Pretoria
2015	Head Teaching Assistant, Program Design in C++ , The University of Pretoria
2015	Teaching Assistant, Data Structures and Algorithms in Java, The University of Pretoria
2014	Teaching Assistant, Introduction to Programming in C, The University of Pretoria

Skills

Licences:	Commercial drone license for small unmanned aircraft systems
Advanced:	Python, C++, ROS, Shell Scripting, LaTeX, Quadrotors, Ubuntu, Windows, MacOS, Unity
Experienced:	C, Java, Solidworks, Keras, Tensorflow, Control Theory, Arduino, Raspberry Pi, Odroid
Proficient:	Lua, C#, Assembly, HTML, CSS, Javascript, ONNX, FPGA, Soldering, Digital Logic

Achievements

2019	National Club Field Hockey Champions - The University of Virginia
2017	Half Iron Man - South Africa
2017	Comrades Ultra Marathon - South Africa
2016	Summited Kilimanjaro - Tanzania
2012	National u18B Field Hockey Team - South Africa